

e. phamous2day@gmail.com

Github: http://github.com/phamous2day

Linkedin https://www.linkedin.com/in/phamdavid

portfolio: http://phamous2day.github.io

### RECENT PROJECTS

<u>HAL-lo Cam</u>: Made a portal to view security camera footage. A Mongo labs database stores the pictures. However, due to its 500MB limit, had to get creative with storing footage, so opted to use image feeds rather than video. AngularJS was leveraged to pull display data exclusively to each user's credentials. Node module bcrypt was use to further secure login credentials.

<u>Coffee Store</u>: Made a functional e-commerce website that can create accounts, offer coffee selections, and live credit card payments. Frontend is composed of AngularJS to bind to backend data. Backend is composed of MongoDB and NodeJS. An obstacle was finding a way to host the backend portion within a budget. I remedied by leveraging Mongo Lab's new service to host the backend while using surge.sh to host the front end all for free.

<u>Pictionary</u>: Originally a "draw-together" app utilizing HTML5 as the canvas and leveraging Socket.IO to provide collaborative experience across computers. Added chat functionality using Node.js to make it further engaging/challenging as a Pictionary game to store "secret words" as the Pictionary topic to draw.

**Sports Map/Ticket Aggregator:** Worked on a team creating an app that maps out current matches using Google Maps and utilizing TicketMaster API to aggregate ticket purchases with corresponding matches. We had a limitation with free accounts that restrict API calls to SportsRadar API, but we offset that by learning to store and call JSON data locally.

### RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

### Year Up

Information Technology Instructor (Jan. 2015—April 2016)

- Facilitated learning through a student-centered environment, ensuring knowledge of content in Computer Hardware, Operating Systems, Project Management, and Network Infrastructure.
- Problem solved site-wide IT issues (wireless connectivity, AV equipment, intermediary between ATL and National headquarters).

# MailChimp

Customer Support Technician (Aug. 2012—July 2014)

- Consistently surpassed average monthly ticket quota by 120%.
- Replicated user issues in test environment and provided documentation to developers.

# AmeriCorps VISTA

Technology Coordinator (Feb. 2011 – Feb 2012)

- Worked in-person and remotely with over 50 staff members when computer issues occurred.
- Conceptualized and created school's first E-Yearbook using HTML and Javascript to offset traditional yearbook costs (ink, shipping, page count, etc).

## **EDUCATION**

DigitalCrafts (May 2016—August 2016)

University of Hawai'i at Mānoa (Aug. 2006—May 2010)

Bachelor of Arts in Journalism